# **Ross Franey**

Software Engineer

#### Profile

Software Engineer for Qualtrics, with 2.5 years of professional experience.

Graduated top of class in Dublin City University with a 1st Class Honours.

I pride myself in having an in-depth understanding of computer science fundamentals, data structures and algorithms, clean coding principals and scalable architecture.

#### Education

### Ba. Software Engineering, Dublin City University

September 2015 — June 2018

- · 1st Class Honor
- Graduated top of class
- · Student Ambassador

### **Employment History**

#### Software Engineer at Qualtrics, Dublin

August 2018 — Present

- Scope and deliver complex, varied projects as the sole engineer, for a number of global clients such as Google, L'Oreal, HSBC and Adidas.
- Work on a large scale SMS distribution product sending 4 million weekly messages, on which I have added a 700% performance increase and an improved queuing system.
- Received internal award for developing "Survey as Code" System, allowing users to manage surveys through Git.
- Designed and delivered a data privacy API for Adidas.
- Received 2 quarterly "exceeds expectations" performance ratings.

#### Software Engineer Intern at Cellusys, Dublin

March 2017 — September 2017

- Serving telecom clients in Java / Clojure based projects
- Delivered feature to distinguish between Arabic / Non-Arabic messages
- · Gained experience with Puppet / Docker / Jenkins

### Personal Projects

#### Machine learning trading platform (Python Web & Android App)

I created this in order to determine the usefulness of Long Short Term Memory neural networks in their predictive capability. Includes Python Django web application, integration with multiple APIs, an Android application, and DynamoDB storage.

#### **Android App - Motion Detection Security System**

Used a python service running on a Raspberry Pi, and a Java Android application to create a system that detects motion and sends the image of

#### **Details**

ross.franey3@mail.dcu.ie

#### **Skills**

Python, PHP, NodeJS, Java, Javascript, React

AWS Lambda, S3, DynamoDB

Scoping & System Design

Technical Writing / Design Documentation

**Databases** 

Data Structures & Algorithms

#### **Hobbies**

Coding challenges / contests Volunteer with refugee groups Personal finance, investing Sports whatever or whoever created that motion to a smart phone through a push notification.

### Messenger Chat Applet

Implementation of an asynchronous chat applet in Java.

https://github.com/rossfraney

## **◄** References

References available upon request